The all-new adventures of the English Lord with the soul of an Indian.
The Return of a Man Called Horse is a western,
adventure film directed by Irvin Kershner.
Lord John Morgan has returned to civilized life in England, but
finds he has nothing but disdain for that life.
Yearning to embrace the simplicity of the American West, and the Sioux tribe he left behind, Morgan returns to the
their land only to discover that they've been decimated by ruthless, government-backed fur traders.
Led by Horse, they fight to repossess their land.
John Morgan / Horse, played by Richard Harris.
Elk Woman, played by Gale Sondergaard.
Zenas, played by Geoffrey Lewis.
Running Bull, played by Jorge Luke.
Blacksmith, played by Jorge Russek.
Chemin De Fer, played by Claudio Brook.
The Return of a Man Called Horse is a 1976 Western film directed
by Irvin Kershner and written by Jack DeWitt.
It is a sequel to the 1970 film A Man Called Horse, in turn based on Dorothy M.
Johnson's short story of the same name, with Richard Harris reprises his role as Horse, a
British aristocrat who has become a member of a tribe of Lakota Sioux.
Other cast members include Gale Sondergaard,
Geoffrey Lewis, and William Lucking.
Like its predecessor, the film is a Mexican-American
co-production, shot primarily on-location in Mexico.
Like its predecessor, the film was largely a critical and financial success,
but was criticized by some for rehashing earlier plot elements.
It was followed by a sequel in 1983, Triumphs of a Man Called Horse.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, indian
territory, native american, revenge, conflict.